In a time when the world of study belonged only to men,
there lived a girl who dared to ask..."why?"
Yentl is a music, drama, romance film directed by Barbra Streisand.
In a time when girls were forbidden to study religious scriptures, a Jewish girl masquerades as
a boy to enter religious training and unexpectedly finds love along the way.
Yentl, played by Barbra Streisand.
Avigdor, played by Mandy Patinkin.
Hadass, played by Amy Irving.
Rebbe Mendel, played by Nehemiah Persoff.
Reb Alter Vishkower, played by Steven Hill.
Shimmele, played by Allan Corduner.
Yentl is a 1983 American romantic musical drama film directed, co-written,
co-produced by, and starring American entertainer Barbra Streisand.
It is based on Isaac Bashevis Singer's short story "Yentl the Yeshiva Boy".
The film incorporates music to tell the story of Yentl Mendel, an Ashkenazi Jewish woman in Poland in 1904 who
decides to disguise herself as a man named Anshel so that she can receive an education in Talmudic law.
The film's musical score and songs, composed by Michel Legrand, with lyrics by Alan and Marilyn Bergman,
include the songs "Papa, Can You Hear Me?" and "The Way He Makes Me Feel", both sung by Streisand.
The film received the Academy Award for Best Original Song Score and the Golden Globe Award for Best Motion Picture—Musical or
Comedy and Best Director for Streisand, making her the first woman to win Best Director at the Golden Globes.
The film explores themes of musical, studies,
disguise, unhappiness, boys' school.
The tone is emotional.